He can save us all.
Elysium is a science fiction, action, drama film directed by Neill Blomkamp.
In the year 2159, two classes of people exist: the very wealthy who live on a pristine man-made
space station called Elysium, and the rest, who live on an overpopulated, ruined Earth.
Secretary Rhodes, a hard line government official, will stop at nothing to enforce
anti-immigration laws and preserve the luxurious lifestyle of the citizens of Elysium.
That doesn’t stop the people of Earth from trying
to get in, by any means they can.
When unlucky Max is backed into a corner, he agrees to take on a daunting mission that, if
successful, will not only save his life, but could bring equality to these polarized worlds.
Max, played by Matt Damon.
Delacourt, played by Jodie Foster.
Kruger, played by Sharlto Copley.
Julio, played by Diego Luna.
Spider, played by Wagner Moura.
Frey, played by Alice Braga.
Elysium is a 2013 American dystopian science fiction action film
written, co-produced, and directed by Neill Blomkamp.
It was Blomkamp's second directorial effort.
The film stars Matt Damon and Jodie Foster alongside Sharlto Copley,
Alice Braga, Diego Luna, Wagner Moura, and William Fichtner.
The film takes place on both a ravaged Earth and a
luxurious artificial world called Elysium.
The film itself offers deliberate social commentary that explores political and sociological themes such as immigration,
overpopulation, transhumanism, health care, worker exploitation, the justice system, technology, and social class issues.
The film was released on August 9, 2013, by Sony Pictures Releasing through the
TriStar Pictures label, in both conventional and IMAX Digital theaters.
It received positive reviews, but critics considered it to be
disappointing after Blomkamp's first film, District 9.
With a budget of $115 million, Elysium was TriStar's most expensive film.
It grossed $286.1 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of future, capitalism,
dystopia, space station, class conflict.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.